I'm
going to go over here.
The monks of Serra are rebuilding their
main debating hall.
Serra was originally the second largest
monastery in Tibet, where more than 6,000
monks studied and lived.
Each morning, the monks gather for the
early morning debate session.
In the monastic universities, the monks
study the classical Buddhist subjects.
These subjects include logic and
epistemology, psychology, philosophy,
cosmology and ethics,
as well as Buddhist meditational theory
and practice.
Traditionally, the monks refine their
scholarly knowledge through debate, both
in the morning session as now, and
again each evening.
The theme being debated here is the
question of what constitutes a particular
act as being virtuous or non-virtuous.
Is an act virtuous or non-virtuous due to
the motivation, the act itself, or the
consequence?
Also, what is the relationship between the
degree of the individual's knowledge or
ignorance, as the act occurs,
and the individual's responsibility for
their actions?
Ten shu, ten.
Ten mundi sken.
Ya, we do not have ten mundi.
It's a good thing that we have a lot of
people.
Ya, we have a lot of people.
We have a lot of people.
Ah, what is it?
What is it?
In addition to their academic studies,
most monks also train as artists,
developing painting,
sculpture, dance, musical and poetry
skills.
The monks also develop and internalize
their scholarly learning through
contemplation, based on classical
meditative
techniques.
In Tibetan society, to become a monk or a
nun is regarded as the highest vocation
and also the
highest service to the community.
Usually, once a week, the Dalai Lama gives
a public audience and a blessing.
The Dalai Lama was recognized at the age
of two as the reincarnate spiritual and
temporal leader of his people.
Until the age of 25, he received the
classical education of a Buddhist monk in
an isolationist Tibet.
Since coming into exile, he has pursued
his studies uninterruptedly and is now
recognized internationally.
as one of the greatest living Buddhist
scholars.
He is regarded by the Tibetan people as
embodying the highest Buddhist values, a
refined insight into the nature of
mind and the human condition, and an
unbiased compassion towards all sentient
beings.
This is Yang
Jian.
Yang Jian.
Is it that way?
Yes.
I'm going to eat.
In Tibetan society, knowledge is handed
down from generation to generation, from
master to student,
primarily through the giving of oral
commentarial explanations to the key
classical texts.
These oral lineages have mainly remained
unbroken from as long ago as the time of
the Buddha himself in the 5th century
BC.
The Dalai Lama has received many of these
oral lineages from his teachers and today
he is beginning the 12-day
explication of a major text known as The
Lamb Illuminating the Five Stages.
This text is a guide to the advanced
levels of deep meditative states.
Before the teaching begins, the monks
recite the Heart Sutra.
which is a quintessence of the Buddha
Shakyamuni's teaching on the way of
realizing the ultimate nature of mind and
phenomena.
Recognizing that our mental and sensory
processes condition all our perceptions
and that ultimately all phenomena are
empty of inherent existence leads to the
realization that the mind's actual nature
is a pure mirror-like awareness,
a blissful union of emptiness and form.
The Heart Sutra is recited very rapidly,
so the text on the subtitles is
summarized.
I
Abba, Dhamma, Radha, Jaya, Naya,
Amin.
I will tell you the
story of
Throughout the year, the monasteries
perform a cycle of rituals for the benefit
of the community.
For seven days and seven nights, in
preparation for one such ritual, the
Ayurpita generates in his mind the
meditational deity, Hayagriva.
Hayagriva represents the state of
awareness in which attachment, aversion
and delusion are dynamically
or wrathfully transformed by a fierce
illumination and compassion.
The blessing will be given using a mystic
dagger here wrapped in a white prayer
scarf.
The illumined compassion of the mind
dances fiercely on the forces of
egocentricity and
overwhelms the obstacles and hindrances of
everyday life.
Rembada gowlo lomo, rembada gowlo lomo
The lay people have confidence that the
contemplative skills of the accomplished
lamas, communicated through the sacred
rituals, can help to remove obstacles in
their daily life and bring inspiration and
protection from suffering.
Thank you.
Hello everyone, I am Sajib Iman.
I am from Zongzi.
I am from Luoyang.
I am from Shunzhu.
I am from Tianshui.
I am from Chongdu.
I am from Zongzi.
I am from Jiamzhen.
I am from Tangtian.
I am from Tangzhen.
The first step is to make the Then by
the check, I should be under the
tally.
Yeah, that's the day.
I am very happy to be able to share my
knowledge with you.
knowledge
with you.
I am very happy to be able to share my
knowledge with you.
I was born in the Kamin area.
I was born in the Kato area.
Good day.
We are here to support the people of
Rangcheng.
Leah.
We are the people of the land.
I am the leader of the Sikasangu tribe.
We have to make sure that the rice is
cooked properly.
If the rice is not cooked properly, the
rice will be hard to cook.
We have to make sure that the rice is
cooked properly.
We have to be very
careful.
We have to be very careful.
and enjoy the video.
Thanks for watching.
I
Welcome to the National Museum of Art of
the United States of America in the United
States of America in the United States of
America
in the United States of America in the
United States of America in the United
States of America in the United States of
America
in the United States of America in the
United States of America in the United
States of America in the United States of
America in the United States of America in
the United
States of America
The story of the story of the story of the
story of the story of the story of the
story of the story
of the story of the story of the story of
the story of the story of the story of the
story of the
story of the story of the story of the
Thank
you.
The
Shhh,
The land is full of water.
The water is very clean.
Thank you.
Oh
You're camping tour.
Do you want to eat the meat?
Yes, I want to eat the meat.
How much is the rice?
I don't know.
I'm not going to do it.
The lagini of the Navasarjaniya home.
Chamu, lagini, rotso.
I
have to give my life for this.
I have to give my life for this.
What is this?
Thank you.
Ah.
Do you know that?
That's what I'm guessing.
Yeah.
You know, young people.
This is the first
time
I've
eaten this.
This is the first time I've eaten this.
Come.
Oh, yeah.
I don't know.
I
Thank you.
Where's the budget?
you
Thank you.
Okay.
I
Hello,
I'm a
Hello friends.
Today we will learn how to make a
beautiful and beautiful flower.
This flower is called the flower of the
flower.
It is a beautiful flower that is not only
beautiful, but also
beautiful.
It is a beautiful flower that is not only
beautiful, but also beautiful.
beautiful,
Welcome to the video of the first video of
the first video of the first video of the
first video of the first video of the
first video of the first video of
the first video of the first video of the
first video of the first video of the
first
Oh,
Hello.
And
here
it is.
Hey yo,
The first time I saw the you look
at halfway using it you
The people of the village are very happy
to see the new
generation of the village.
They are very happy to see the new
We have to be careful.
When I was young, I was a farmer.
I was a farmer in Dubai.
I don't know.
The people who are living here are the
ones who are the most affected by the war.
They are the ones who are the most
affected by the war.
I was a
young man, I was very happy to see him.
you're going to ask them, I'll just send
that time to.
I was very happy to see that.
The people who are living here are the
ones who have the most money.
They are the ones who have the most money.
They are the ones who have the
most money.
They are the ones who have the most money.
I am going to take the table and come
back.
The people of the village were very happy.
They were very happy.
Thank
you.
Welcome to the
Don't do it, everyone
I'm 80 years old.
I'm 23 years old.
Welcome to the National Museum of
Art
Abijin du tibet, lebanon, tukum bu opa me
la nuwa, na jujijin jindile,
ajiungan jirung.
HOOP
HOOP HOOP
Thank you.